wne.edu 2019-07-04

# Website Privacy Policy

This privacy notice describes how Western New England University ("we", "our" or "us") collects and processes personal information about you through https://www.wne.edu and all other Western New England University websites and applications that link this privacy notice or e.g. for employees, through the course of your employment with Western New England University, how we use and protect this information, and your rights in relation to this information.

This privacy notice applies to all personal information we collect or process about you. Personal information is information, or a combination of pieces of information, that could reasonably allow you to be identified.

### What information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?

######   
Automatically Collected Information

Our web servers automatically collect information from site visitors, such as IP addresses and browser information, in order to optimize users' web experience and analyze traffic patterns. The web servers gather information about the particulars of a visitor's visit through the University web site such as the web page from which a visitor enters the site, the pages within the site visited, how long a visitor is on the site, and other such information that will help Western New England University evaluate and improve its site. This information is collected and analyzed on a summary basis only. It is not personally identifiable.

###### Volunteered Information

We collect personally identifiable information only when voluntarily provided by website users. We only receive personal information about site visitors through our online forms. When using our site, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, social security number, date of birth or any combination of data that could be used to identify you. This information is collected for the purposes of recruitment, admission to the University, communications, academics, verification of identity,account details (e.g. username and password) and transaction details (e.g. when you pay tuition or make purchases).

### When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you visit our site, register on our site, subscribe to a newsletter, fill out a form, use live chat, open a support ticket or otherwise enter information on our site.

## How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for a newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.
  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To allow us to better respond to your customer service requests.
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.
  * To quickly process your transactions.
  * To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.
  * To follow up with you after correspondence (live chat, email or phone inquiries)
  * To communicate with you, for example, about changes to terms and conditions or if you contact us with questions.
  * Exercising our rights, for example, to detect, prevent respond to fraud claims, intellectual property infringement claims or violations of law or our Terms of Use or Terms of Service.

### CONFIDENTIALITY OF STUDENT RECORDS (FERPA)

Western New England University adheres to a policy of compliance with the Family Educational Rights Privacy Act (FERPA).  The policy is found seperately as part of the Student Handbook.

### How do we protect your information?

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We implement a variety of security measures when a user places an order, enters, submits, or accesses their information. These measures are designed to maintain the safety of your personal information.

While most voluntary information is only maintained long enough to provide the specific service requested, some personally identifiable information may be retained as part of backup procedures. In addition, some personally identifiable information may be added to University databases to be used for other University business and academic purposes. Please refer to our Written Information Security Program (WISP) for more information.

### Do we use 'cookies'?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site's or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, they are used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

#### If users disable cookies in their browser:

If you turn cookies off, some features will be disabled. Some of the features make your site experience more efficient and may not function properly.

You may not be able to login, view grades, pay bills, or access other services. However, many of these tasks can be done over the telephone.

### Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property or safety. 

### Third-party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### Google

We use Google Analytics to analyze our websites usage to improve customer engagement.

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

### YOUR RIGHTS OVER YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

You have certain rights regarding the personal information we hold about you, subject to local law. These may include the right to access, correct, delete, restrict or object to our use of, or receive a portable copy in a usable electronic format of your personal information. You also may have a right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection or privacy regulator.

### INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFER

Your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a country that is not regarded as providing the same level of protection for personal information as the laws of your home country, and may be available to the government of those countries under a lawful order made in those countries.

We have put in place appropriate safeguards (such as contractual commitments) in accordance with applicable legal requirements to provide adequate protections for your personal information.

### CONTACTING US

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact us using the information below:

**[www.wne.edu  
](http://www.wne.edu/)** **1215 Wilbraham Road  
** **Springfield, MA 01119  
** **United States  
** **[webmaster@wne.edu  
](mailto:webmaster@wne.edu)** **413-782-3111**

**Last Edited on 2018-10-23**
